Kwang il Lee



ADDRESS 9-6, Deungchon-ro 13ba-gil, PHONE +82 1027495620

Gangseo-gu, Seoul, 07739,

Republic of Korea

EMAIL bitjjangi@gmail.com DATE / PLACE OF 1978-02-21 / Seoul

BIRTH

Korean ONLINE-CV https://cv.papajun.xyz/

ONLINE-CV http://blog.papajun.xyz/chris/cv/ PUBLIC_PROFILE

http://blog.papajun.xyz/chris/cv/ PUBLIC_PROFILE http://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-lee-

b6a00520

Profile

NATIONALITY

(RESPEC.JS)

My name is chris lee who is QA manager.

I have worked as SQA: Browser, web app, web rumtime, automotive platform.

Also, I had participated in standards activity as the following

- · contributor of W3C widget specification,
- · editor of HKMC automotive specification,
- · contributor of WAC/bondi test case.

I have interesting in the SQA, automated test tool, standards activity.

I have a pride in my job and I will be performed perfectly the work assigned to me.

Employment History

Nov 2015 - Present

SEOUL

SQA Manager, Service Operator, Technical Support

Daliworks

In Daliworks, the startup of the IoT platform, I working on several roles.

The role as the operator for Thing+, IoT platform. The role as Quality control for IoT platform, IoT portal, IoT embedded.

The role as Technical Support are responded to inquiries about interlocking development of partner companies and customers.

And I taken charge of the training event like the external training and hackathon event

Jul 2006 - Nov 2015

PANKYO

QCC Team manager

Obigo

I have been in Obigo for 10 years and there have been many changes in the product.

The obigo product was a mobile solution when I joined and I was in charge of the messaging part.

Here are the product lines I was responsible for:

Messaging - WAP browser - Full browser - Web platform (mobile - TV - Automotive) I had work as test leader in QA organization and became team manager in 2012.

When obigo develope a web platform with a group called WAC, I became a WAC contributor. I supported personally to make the W3C widget specification and I became a contributor of W3C

Oct 2005 - Jul 2006

SEOUL

Web Developer

Fuzwire

Development of web site

- http://www.i-challenge.co.kr
- http://www.samsungsdi.com

Feb 2005 - Aug 2005

SEOUL

QE

Modacom

Verification & validation against the LG Cyon phones.

(contract based position)

Nov 2002 - Dec 2004

SEOUL

Web Content Developer

MDNT

In MDNT

Development of web site

- Planning & Web programming
- Developing the VR(Virtual Reality)
- Planning & execution of Shanghai Game Exhibition for Wemade co., Ltd.

In E-systems

- web developer & master
- Sale of USB flash memory and managing the shopping mall.
- · Developing and managing prestigious shopping malls (robinhood, luxury 24

Education

Mar 2010 - Feb 2012

SEOUL

Korea national open University

BSc in Computer Science

• Major: computer science

• Thesis: UX evaluation against Mobile browser

Mar 1996 - Feb 2001

INCHEON

Inha Technical College

ASc in Mechatronics

- · Major. mechatronics
- Thesis: Industrial Robot control technology

Skills

node.js BEST API HTML5/CSS

MS office

• • • •

• • • •

Familiarity of Automated test tool • • • sketch/Photoshop

Qualification

Jan 2008

ISTQB

ISTQB (International Software Testing Qualifications Board)

FL

Nov 2001

SUN (ORACLE)

SCJP (Sun Certified JAVA Program)

Stanard Activity (contributor)

W3C

web app: Digital-signature

W3C

http://dev.w3.org/2006/waf/widgets-digsig/imp-report/

Not do business job but personally job

web app: Interface

W3C

http://dev.w3.org/2006/waf/widgets-api/imp-report/

Not do business job but personally job

W3C

W3C

web app: Packaged-Web-Apps

http://dev.w3.org/2006/waf/widgets/imp-report/

Not do business job but personally job

web ap : View-mode

http://dev.w3.org/2006/waf/widgets-vmmf/imp-report/

Not do business job but personally job

web app: WARP

M3C

http://dev.w3.org/2006/waf/widgets-access/imp-report/

Not do business job but personally job

(web platform) Automotive-specification

HYUNDAI MOTORS

http://blog.papajun.xyz/chris/cv/automotive.html

Test owner

WAC

- Participated in WAC test fest (3 times) contribute WAC test asset.
- Tests owner for WAC tests messaging, task, calendar, contact.